Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Engineering Physics -

Notice Period: 1 Month

Minor in CS]

PRAKHAR BANSAL () Featured

Software Engineer seeking role in Software Development, Application
Development, Application Support, Project Management, Quality Management, Program
Management, Requirement Gathering, Software
Testing, C, C++, Python, Java, MATLAB, SQL



Current Designation: Quant Software Developer

Current Company: Daksh Trading

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Hong Kong, United States (US), Netherlands

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: Banking/Financial Services/Broking

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Development, Application Development, Application Support, Project

Management, Quality Management, Program Management, Requirement Gathering, Software

Testing,C,C++,Python,Java,MATLAB,SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

IIT Delhi Alumni with over 1 year of experience in rendering technical skills for Software Development for actively driving organizational goals

Insightful knowledge on various stages of the SDLC; well versed in designing and implementing modules for Derivatives Trading

Developed testing environment for strategies; supported the teams in designing and developing software modules Worked on ultra-low latency technologies like ef-vi (Kernel Bypass)

Experienced with PostgreSQL and used its C++ libraries in low latency modules to facilitate trading

Technical know-how entails exposure to technologies like Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Mining, & Algorithms

Possess a go-getter attitude along with strong communication, coordination, analytical & problem-solving capabilities

Work Experience

Daksh Trading as Quant Software Developer Jan 2021 to Till Date

Low Latency C++ Development

Acceletrade as Quant Software Developer

Jun 2020 to Dec 2020

B3 hardware integration

APT Portfolio Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer (Infrastructure)

Jan 2019 to May 2020

Key Result Areas:

Worked in low-latency C++ for designing and implementing modules for derivatives trading

Designed and developed testing environment for strategies using live market data

Coordinated with hardware team in designing and developing software modules to manage FPGA

Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt it to new hardware, upgrade interfaces and improve performance

Optimized and adapted the platform by taking advantage of technology advancements in networking and systems

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Engineering Physics -Minor in CS) from INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, DELHI in 2019

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C, C++, Python, Linux, Bash	
SQL, Java, MATLAB, MongoDB	
LaTeX, BOOST, Scikit, Pandas	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
French				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time